Ramesh Vishnoi

rameshvishnoi
90904@gmail.com | +917498011904 | Mumbai, India | linkedin.com/in/rameshvishnoi
/ | github.com/rameshvishnoi
90904

SUMMARY

A Senior Frontend Engineer with 7 years of JavaScript development experience. Experienced in every single step of product development and delivery. Authored Multiple mobile app using React native and React apps from scratch. Lead team of engineers in planning, execution and delivering on various projects.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Lead, Verak

Jun 2021 - Present

- Build a Multiple Web platform using ReactJs to support different stakeholders in the commercial insurance sale lifecycle.
- Led team of engineers in building, planning and execution of multiple products
- Interviewed, Recruited and Trained candidates for ReactJs roles.

Cofounder and CTO, Swedit

Feb 2021 - Jun 2021

- Authored Swedit Mobile app using React Native, reached 1000+ downloads in Android and IOS app store
- Authored Community builder platform for managing content for app using React.JS
- Designed and Configured scalable backend infrastructure on Firebase.
- Integrate ML model for counting Exercise repetition using live camera feed in React native App.
- Implemented automated personalized email and notifications flow.
- Authored Running activity tracker for mobile devices.
- Integrated React native app with ios Health, Google Fit, Strava, Suunto, Mapmyrun, Fitbit

Senior Frontend Engineer, Appivo

Aug 2018 - Jan 2021

- Collaborated in Visual builder for creating android/ios and web apps using Vuejs
- Used AST to create javascript class based code snippet suggestions and autocompletion using TernJs and AceEditor
- Implemented autogeneration logic to update wordpress based documentation site
- Implemented Theming based View/Page mechanism using template engine
- Mentored junior developers in write scalable, readable bug free code

Full Stack Engineer, Disprz

Dec 2016 - Jun 2018

- Implemented Corporate solution for training, engaging, skill based learning for employees using ReactJs, DotNet.
- Implemented New Education solution for catering K12
- Authored flash card based fun learning activity
- Contributed to quiz based learning activity, supported development of Mobile application in react native

React Native Developer, Reliance Jio

Dec 2015 - Nov 2016

- Implemented Jio Expressnews Mobile app on Android and iOS in React native, downloaded by 10 Million users on android playstore.
- Created multiple custom components for in-house apps using react native such as React native cardboard, React native exoplayer, KRpano
- $\bullet \ \ Authored \ Recycler \ List View \ in \ React \ native \ (https://github.com/rameshvishnoi90904/react-native-recycler-listview)$
- Showcased potential usage of React native in main stream media applications offering Live streaming such as JioCinema and JioTv. Demonstrated single codebase usage for iOS and Android apps.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

Jun 2011 - Jul 2015

Ramrao Adik Institute of Technology

Percentage: 69

SKILLS

Mobile App Development: React Native, Git, react.js Web Development: Vuejs, Git, html, css, react.js, web